A Finding Aid to the Joseph Lindon Smith Papers, 1647-1965, bulk 1873-1965, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Theatrical Production Files, 1897-1950; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; (Box 6-7, 10; 1.2 linear feet)
  - Script for Golden Jubilee Pageant at Buffalo Fine Arts Academy, 1912; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
  - File for the Tiffany Fete The Quest of Beauty, 1913-1916; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Script for Play Nuzhat-Fi-Bilad-El-Ajam, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Notes and Photographs from Masque of the Blue Garden, 1913; Archival Resource Key; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 10) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Clippings and Photographs from Masque Sanctuary, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - File for the St. Louis Pageant and Masque, 1913-1914; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 9-11)
  - File for Pageant Pan and the Star, 1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Script Notes for an Untitled Play, 1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - File for Masque The Tempest, 1916; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - File for Play As You Like It, 1916; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - File for Red Cross Pageant The Standard Bearers, 1916-1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - File for Pageant The Building of the Temple, 1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - File for Play Love of Country, 1917 and 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - File for the Memphis Pageant, 1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - File for Play The Pearl and the Pirate, 1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - File for Pageant Once Upon a Time, 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - File for the Amherst Centennial Pageant, 1921; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - File for the Submarine Ball, 1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - File for the Halloween Drama, 1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Script for Play The Loon's Laughter, 1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - File for an Untitled Tavern Play, 1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - File for Play The Lighthouse, 1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Program for Play The Enchanting Adventure, 1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - File for the Massachusetts Bay Colony Tercentenary Pageant, 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - File for Play Brewster's Dark Pond, Presented for Amelia Earhart, 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - File for Masque The Royal Gift, 1933; Archival Resource Key; (7 folders) (Box 7, Folder 31-37)
  - File for the Play for the Century Association, 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - File for Play Who could Imagine Such Happenings?, 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - File for the "Japanese Play,", 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - File for an Untitled Play, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - File for Play The Golden Key, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - File for Pageant The Children's Crusade, 1940; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 43-45)
  - File for the Benefit for Hampshire, England, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Script for Pageant Voices Across the Sea, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - File for the Pageant Honoring Abbott Thayer, 1941-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - File for an Untitled Play at the Club, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - File for Plays The Princess and the Peasant and The Old Chinese Artist Laughs at Last, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - File for Pageant at Harvard, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - File for Benefit Auction, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - File for Play Columbia in Conference or Columbia on Strike, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - File for Pageant Children's Laughter, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - File for Pantomime A Chinese Landscape, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Script for the "Elizabethan Play,", 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - File for Play The President's Dilemma, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - File for Play John Singleton Copley, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - File for Play Through Magic Spectacles, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - File for Play Peace Greets Dublin, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - File for the Supper Party Play, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - File for Play The Warrior Comes Home, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - File for Play Then and Now, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - File for Play It's Time It Happened, 1949; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 64-65)
  - Script for the Golden Wedding Play, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - File for Play A Possible Solution, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Writing Fragments for Theatrical Productions, undated; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 68-69)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs from Unidentified Theatrical Productions, undated; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 70-72)
  - Oversized Musical Magazine Etude for Play Jack Frost in Midsummer, 1949; Archival Resource Key; (from Box 6, Folder 77) (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Photographs of Masque of the Blue Garden, 1913; Archival Resource Key; (from Box 7, Folder 7) (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Art Works, 1932-1943; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; (Box 8, 10; 8 folders)
  Art work includes a sketchbook with extensive notes, a painting, drawings by Joseph Lindon Smith, and prints by other artists.
  - Sketchbook/Notebook, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Drawings, 1932, undated; Archival Resource Key; (4 folders;Oversized Material Housed in Box 10) (Box 8, Folder 2-5)
  - Illustrated Book The Juvenile Picture Book by E. G. Smith, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Drawings by Smith's Children, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Prints, 1933-1943, undated; Archival Resource Key; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 10) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Oversized Drawings, undated; Archival Resource Key; (from Box 8, Folder 6) (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Painting on Panel, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Print, 1943; Archival Resource Key; (from Box 8, Folder 8) (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Scrapbook, 1888-1901; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; (Box 8; 1 folder)
  A scrapbook contains clippings and an exhibition catalog from the St. Botolph Club.
  - Scrapbook, 1888-1901; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Printed Material, 1723-1963; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; (Box 8, OV 11; 0.8 linear feet)
  Printed material includes clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, press releases, programs, booklets, brochures, and books.
  - Clippings, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1759; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1898-1912; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1915-1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1920-1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1928-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1931; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 16-17)
  - Clippings, 1932-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Clippings, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Clippings, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Clippings, 1940-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Clippings, 1945-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Clippings, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Clippings, 1950-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Clippings, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, 1953-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Clippings, 1956; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 30-32)
  - Clippings, 1957-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - By-Laws and Newsletters for the American Research Center in Egypt, Inc., 1950-1954; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 34-35)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for the Smith Family, 1891-1953, undated; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 36-37)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Others, 1949-1952, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Press Releases, 1920-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Programs, 1900-1963, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Booklet Country Life in Ancient Egypt, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Booklet Sculptures Indiennes de la Collection Paul Mallon by Victor Goloubew, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Booklet Spiritual Songs for Children by J. Wright, 1784; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Booklet A Poem on the Lord's Day: Together with Acrostics on General Washington and President Adams, 1800; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Booklet A Short Account of the Last Sickness and Death of Maria Mott, 1817; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Booklet The American Tract Magazine, 1824; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Booklet Synopsis of Phrenology, 1849; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Booklet Un Mese Nella Necropoli di Tebe by A. Malvezzi, 1905; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Booklet The Introductory Gresham Lecture by F. M. Sandwith, 1907; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Booklet L'Isola del Paradiso: Un Viaggio a Ceylon, 1908; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Booklet Jarash, 1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Booklet Seminole Indians, 1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Booklet Treaty of Alliance, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Booklet Traffic in Opium and Other Dangerous Drugs, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Booklet The Morley Collection of Spanish Colonial Ecclesiastical Art, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Booklet The Thursday Evening Club of Boston by Reginald Fitz, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Booklet Joseph Lindon Smith - The Man and the Artist by Dr. M. Mahdi Allam, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Booklet The Wisdom of Father Andrew by Kathleen E. Burne, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Booklet Angela Behind the Steel Drape by Angela Brown, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Book Ed Dakhleh Oasis by H. E. Winlock, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Book The Fellaheen by Father Henry Ayrout, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Brochures for Book Tombs, Temples, and Ancient Art by Joseph Lindon Smith, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Miscellaneous Brochures, 1929-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Picture Postcards, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Reproductions of Art Work, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1723-1945; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders;Oversized Material Housed in OV 11) (Box 8, Folder 66-67)
  - Oversized Certificate from Imperial Reception at Carnival Palace in New Orleans, 1891; Archival Resource Key; (from Box 8, Folder 66) (Oversize 11)
  - Oversized Printed Salute to Tommy Atkins from George Stewart, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 11)
- Photographs, 1884-1956; Series 10; Archival Resource Key; (Box 8-10; 0.5 linear feet)
  Photographs are of Smith, his family, friends, exhibition installations, scenes from World War I, travel scenes, and art work by Smith.
  - Joseph Lindon Smith, 1910-1947; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 68-69)
  - Family Members, 1944-1951, undated; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 70-71)
  - Friends, 1884-1955; Archival Resource Key; (5 folders) (Box 8, Folder 72-76)
  - Scenes from World War I, 1918-1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Unidentified Exhibition Installation, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Exhibition Installation at Atlanta Base, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Exhibition Installation for Harvard Tercentenary, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Exhibition Installation Honoring George Reisner, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Exhibition Installation in Book Store, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Travel to Cambodia, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Travel to Egypt, undated; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 2-4)
  - Travel to India, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Travel to Italy (Rome), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Travel to Japan, 1901-1910, undated; Archival Resource Key; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 10) (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
  - Travel to Jordan (Petra), 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Travel to Mexico, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Travel to Persia (Persepolis), 1934; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 11-13)
  - Travel to the United States (Southwest), 1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Buildings, undated; Archival Resource Key; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 10) (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Art Work by Joseph Lindon Smith from Cambodia, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Art Work by Joseph Lindon Smith from Egypt, undated; Archival Resource Key; (5 folders) (Box 9, Folder 17-21)
  - Art Work by Joseph Lindon Smith from Italy (Rome), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Art Work by Joseph Lindon Smith from Japan, undated; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 23-24)
  - Art Work by Joseph Lindon Smith from Java, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Art Work by Joseph Lindon Smith from Jordan (Petra), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Art Work by Joseph Lindon Smith from Mexico, undated; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 27-28)
  - Art Work by Joseph Lindon Smith from Persia (Persepolis), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous Art Work by Joseph Lindon Smith, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous Art Work by Others, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Oversized Photographs of Art Work from Japan, undated; Archival Resource Key; from Box 9, Folder 8 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Oversized Photograph of a Minaret in an Unidentified Country, undated; Archival Resource Key; from Box 9, Folder 15 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Audio Recordings, 1956; Series 11; Archival Resource Key; (Box 9, 10; 2 folders)
  Audio recordings consist of radio interviews with Barry Faulkner and Corinna Lindon Smith, a radio program about Joseph Lindon Smith, and a fragment of an additional interview with Corinna Smith. Original recordings are on four sound discs, all of which were created at WKNE radio in Keene, NH.
  Arrangement note
  All of the sound recordings in this series have been digitized for research access. Previous copies made on cassette are also available.
  - Interview with Barry Faulkner conducted by Ruth Redington about Joseph Lindon Smith, 1956; Archival Resource Key; (1 original sound disc, 1 duplicate sound cassette, oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 9, Folder 32, Item 1)
    Side 2 of this recording contains a 9-minute fragment of an interview with Corinna Smith conducted by Ted Sawyer.
  - Interview with Corinna Smith conducted by Howard E. Wheelock about Joseph Lindon Smith, 1956; Archival Resource Key; (1 original sound disc, 1 duplicate sound cassette, oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 9, Folder 32, Item 2)
  - "Tombs, Temples, and Ancient Art: Joseph Lindon Smith,", 1956; Archival Resource Key; (2 original sound discs, 2 duplicate sound cassettes, oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 9, Folder 32, Item 3)
  - Oversized Sound Recordings, 1956; Archival Resource Key; (from Box 9, folder 32) (Box 10, Folder 7)